A Guide to the E. Carter Foster Papers, 1916-1973
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
E. Carter Foster Papers, 1916-1973
The Library of Virginia
50300
1.75 cubic feet (5 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Anne C. Hindman, Gordonsville.
Biographical Information
Edward Carter Foster was born on 5 January 1895. He was the son of James Robert Foster (1849-1919) and Mary deButts Carter (1871-1938). He attended Episcopal High School and the University of Virginia. Foster was an avid horseman, and bred horses at his farm "Hillside" near The Plains, Fauquier County, Virginia. He was also a vestryman and treasurer of Grace Episcopal Church. Foster married 1) Francis B. Broaddus (1885-1980) on 16 September 1924. They divorced in 1934. He married 2) Anne Foster (1908-1994) of London, England on 8 November 1941. Carter Foster died on 19 January 1973, and is buried on the family farm "Whitewood."
Scope and Content
Papers, 1916-1973, of E. Carter Foster (1895-1973) of The Plains, Fauquier County, Virginia. Includes an account book and day book, deeds, diaries, guest registers, memorandum books, and information relating to his interest in horse breeding and racing, and Jones (or Norwich) terriers. There are also sympathy cards and notes written to his family upon his death in 1973.
Contents List
- Account Book - Hilton, 1942-1943. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Address Book. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Articles and Essays by E. Carter Foster. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Check Registers, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence - Miscellaneous. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Day Book - Hilton, 1942-1943. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Deeds. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Diaries, 1916-1953. (Box 4)
- Diaries, 1967-1973. (Box 5)
- Farm and Orchard Birds. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Genealogical Notes. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Guest Registers, 1943-1945, 1946-1947. (Box 5)
- Horse Racing and Breeding - Publications. (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
- Horse Worms. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Jones Terriers/Norwich Terriers. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Memorandum Books. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Miscellaneous. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Nutrition. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Periodic Opthalmia (Moon Blindness). (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Photographs. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Plains Riding Club. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Plats. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Publications - History. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Sympathy Cards and Notes. (Box 2, Folder 6-13)
- Sympathy Cards and Notes. (Box 3, Folder 1-5)